<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://narekyan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://narekyan.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2022-10-04T17:36:10+00:00</updated><id>https://narekyan.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">2 main motives of humankind or how to stay a human.</title><link href="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/2-main-motives-huamns/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 main motives of humankind or how to stay a human." /><published>2022-10-04T10:08:16+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-04T10:08:16+00:00</updated><id>https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/2-main-motives-huamns</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/2-main-motives-huamns/"><![CDATA[<p>From the book The Denial of Death written by Ernest Becker, we can take out that humans have 2 anthropological wants, motives that didn’t go anywhere in the 21st century. Ernest Becker was an American cultural anthropologist. Anthropology is the scientific study of humanity, concerned with human behavior, human biology, cultures, societies, and linguistics, in both the present and past, including past human species.
<br /><br />
2 main motives are the following : <b>Belonging to something larger and Feeling special</b>. Moving forward I can say we have to balance these motives.</p>
<div class="row">
    <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0">
        <figure>

  <picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/motives-480.webp" />
    <source media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/motives-800.webp" />
    <source media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/motives-1400.webp" />
    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" src="/assets/img/motives.png" title="image" />

  </picture>

</figure>

    </div>
</div>
<p><br />
Yes, dear ladies and gentlemen, we all know that we are mortal, and at some point we will not be, but life will continue to evolve. Since people cannot overcome this fact, we begin to think that, okay, even if we are going to be erased from life, then at least let’s live an important and vital life)). <i>This thing in fact can make life suffer less painful.</i> People do many things to feel important, you name it. People even go to jobs and make money)) , they are use social networks , buy things and also eat too much.
<br /><br />
Because life is very dynamic nowadays, our brain is always under constant overstimulation. And at some point, our behavior can become pathological.</p>
<ul>
<li>If someone will be too focused on the first motivation they for sure will become anxious. They will start to give too much and lose themself, and in the end, lose humanity. This means these individuals will start to forget about them and become useless and pointless.</li>
<li>If someone is too focused on the second motivation, they can suddenly become a narcissist, they will begin to give almost nothing to others, which again means they will lose their humanity. This means that these people will begin to love only themselves, and also in others they will begin to love and seek only love directed at them.</li>
</ul>
<p>So we have to give ourselves to others without losing ourselves. We have to share equality and support ,and as a result, we will end up in equilibriums, in balance. We must take care of ourselves first.
<br />
Smaller things that people need to start to appreciate are family, friends which will satisfy the motivation to be part of something larger, and self-expression, which can a little bit satisfy the motivation to feel special.
We need to make others feel important and that way we should feel important and together we will be something larger then we ourselves. We must be in what I call evolutionary attractive communication. Also in the workplace, we have to appreciate the work of employees and coworkers. We have to respect others and create things together. You can find some approaches <a href="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/how-to-live-this-life/">here</a> about how to live life constructively.
<br /><br />
Well, there is also one more question: why we need to be human and respect others at all? We just need to always remember that we are stronger together and this is not a romantic statement.
<br />
Thanks for reading , now I will go and eat my greek salad to feel special and wait for your comments and thoughts to feel part of something larger.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts" /><category term="about" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[idea sharing]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to live this life</title><link href="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/how-to-live-this-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to live this life" /><published>2022-06-02T12:18:16+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-02T12:18:16+00:00</updated><id>https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/how-to-live-this-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/how-to-live-this-life/"><![CDATA[<p>We all live this life first time and we have only basic concepts in our genes about what life is look like. We need to go through life, give it a shot and see what we can achieve or feel. Or we can read books and use other people’s experiences. Seems easy, right, but in practice, it’s not. Why? Because we are hoomans. Period.
<br />
I want to share my opinion and experience about why it is not easy to live this life and share with you some practical approaches.
<br />
I’m mainly a software engineer, I say mainly because I don’t like to be associated with only my profession. Once in the school, in an informatics lesson where we were learning some basic concepts of programming I(read my brain) realized that “Oh we can actually automate things, do something once and reuse the solution after that, great”. Yes here we can do the first inference, our brains are lazy). After that, I decided to go with the programmer path. I studied computer science at university and started to work as a programmer. Started to receive first salaries. I started to think about how I wanted to live this life.
<br /></p>
<ul>
   <li>First thing is finances. My first books were about successful people and about their life paths as examples of life, as a consequence started to think about success, and this followed to financial stability topic. This is one of the main pillars of how to live this life. 
The first book about finance was “Rich dad, poor dad”. From my today’s view, it is a little bit naive book, but at that period it gave me the idea that I can control something, in this case, finances, and have achievements. This gave me the feeling that I can make money and feel good. But again we are humans and everything is not that easy.</li>
    <li>The next thing we have to consider is our neural system. It is really big, and they say home-sapience is the most intelligent mammal so far. That means our neural system is extra compared to our bodies. This makes us not as determined as animals. And I read that our neural system becomes self-aware later in our 20s. We can call this process Constant ripening. Whether we want it or not, we become more and more self-aware during this time. Carl Jung used a very good term The shadow, which refers to parts of our whole self that we don't know about ourselves yet. So the fact of the existence of this shadow and fact that our neural system is complex makes our connection to the world around us a complex process.</li>
    <li>One more thing is the Dominance principle in the brain. As the neural system advances, we started to want many things, and we start to receive much more signals from our bodies as well.
Life itself becomes a complex process because we are complex for ourselves. We start to have inner conflicts and we start to ask what is important to ourselves cause we don't have that many resources to provide for all our wants. The neural system has lower parts, from the mammal level, like the vagus nerve, and also has higher parts, action result acceptors, like dynamic stereotyping systems. At the same time, different parts of our neural system have different architectures, which motivate different behaviors.</li>
</ul>
<p>At some point, our brain will need and decide to find or create a system where it can function properly and with discipline. There are plenty of systems on the internet, but I only know some of them and have tried only a couple of them. An interesting one is Japanese ikigai, I need to read it more still and marinade it to see what results and feelings it can bring.
<br />
I want to share 3 concepts that help me.
<br /></p>
<ul>
    <li>The first one is from positive psychology, here is the image. 
<div class="row">
    <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0">
        <figure>

  <picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/balance-480.webp" />
    <source media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/balance-800.webp" />
    <source media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/balance-1400.webp" />
    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" src="/assets/img/balance.png" title="" />

  </picture>

</figure>

    </div>
</div>
Basically, this is like a reminder and you have to keep the balance you choose between these 4 components of life. You give them a priority and then keep them. </li>
    <li>Next is the Emotional ladder. Here is the image. 
<div class="row">
    <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0">
        <figure>

  <picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/ladder-480.webp" />
    <source media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/ladder-800.webp" />
    <source media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/ladder-1400.webp" />
    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" src="/assets/img/ladder.png" title="" />

  </picture>

</figure>

    </div>
</div>
Here you need to recognize at what emotional level you are right now, and with questioning yourself go up and up on this ladder until you can start to feel the emotion that is appropriate to the current situation.</li>
    <li>And the last one is the Lean startup approach, here is the image. 
<div class="row">
    <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0">
        <figure>

  <picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/lean-480.webp" />
    <source media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/lean-800.webp" />
    <source media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/lean-1400.webp" />
    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" src="/assets/img/lean.png" title="example image" />

  </picture>

</figure>

    </div>
</div>
Here you are acting iteratively and delivering results without judging yourself. This is the same Constant ripening approach.</li>
</ul>
<p>So here is my experience of understanding how to live this life. Of course, you have to have goals. And you can try these approaches in your daily life and see will they be effective for your goals.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts" /><category term="about" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[my experience of practical approaches]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">remote working</title><link href="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/remote-working/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="remote working" /><published>2022-04-30T22:21:16+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-30T22:21:16+00:00</updated><id>https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/remote-working</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2022/remote-working/"><![CDATA[<p>Seems a new trend.
I’ve been working remotely even before the pandemic. After the pandemic, it became mainstream. Before pandemic this way of working was called freelance) but I was always using the wording remote. Even today there are people who say freelance). 
<br />
In this half-baked article, I want to share with you how I see and feel remote work, its advantages, and disadvantages from my view. This is going to be my reflection on my recent work experience.
<br />
I live in Yerevan, some people say silicon valley of Caucasus. Some sort of true, Yerevan has good weather and there are startups with good people, professionals and investments. No FAANG or FAANGoid company presence yet.
<br />
So in general, I like working remotely. First of all, on an intuitive level,  you can have the smell of freedom. I want to mention the 4 main practical day-to-day advantages of remote work and at the same time dark sides of these advantages.</p>
<ul>
    <li>First thing first, you work when you want. More concrete you can decide when to wake up, and of course, most probably you’ll wake up when you get your sleep fully, which is great. I am used to doing this in this way, some days I wake up at 9 am, some days around 12 pm. I based on what I have to do that day, decide to sleep more or less.</li>
    <li>Second, you have the freedom of scheduling your day, I would say you decide your agenda. When you can do your tasks, what tasks do first, what to keep for later. I can say I have a more authentic way of working. You don't have to go to the office where you are not always as productive as you want and you have to deal with redundant requirements. I work from home and sometimes choose coworking.</li>
    <li>The next point is related to knowledge and culture sharing. Being working with abroad people from Europe and America brings you to a state where you can get new knowledge of how to interact in the team in a more respectful and efficient way.</li>
    <li>And finally, I want to say the financial part, it can be improved because you can work for European/American companies.</li>
</ul>
<p>Pretty good huh.</p>
<hr />

<p>And here are the disadvantages, the dark sides. Let’s show off them.
<br /></p>
<ul>
    <li>Because I decide when to wake up, it makes me a little lazy, and I lose some level of discipline, despite I found a solution for this. I go to the gym and keep myself disciplined.</li>
    <li>Then we have an issue with not going to an office, here you are losing connections with people who can be interesting to you, you don't see people too often, you can only interact with them on online platforms.</li>
    <li>Next, because you work more with other countries' cultures, you are losing your country's way of working, and you can become less connected to your country. At the same time, you don't get full benefits from other countries as well, for ex., many companies don't give you share options.</li> 
    <li>And the last one is related to compensation. From first sight there is no disadvantage here)), but what is bad is that you start to think about money as the only stimuli of work, that's really bad. <blockquote> You just need to remember money won't make you smart. </blockquote></li>
</ul>
<p>This were my reflection on working remotely, I think I may come time to time to this article and do updates.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts" /><category term="remote" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[reflextion on remote work]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test post with formatting and links</title><link href="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2015/formatting-and-links/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test post with formatting and links" /><published>2015-03-15T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2015-03-15T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2015/formatting-and-links</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://narekyan.github.io/blog/2015/formatting-and-links/"><![CDATA[<p>Jean shorts raw denim Vice normcore, art party High Life PBR skateboard stumptown vinyl kitsch. Four loko meh 8-bit, tousled banh mi tilde forage Schlitz dreamcatcher twee 3 wolf moon. Chambray asymmetrical paleo salvia, sartorial umami four loko master cleanse drinking vinegar brunch. <a href="https://www.pinterest.com">Pinterest</a> DIY authentic Schlitz, hoodie Intelligentsia butcher trust fund brunch shabby chic Kickstarter forage flexitarian. Direct trade <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold-pressed_juice">cold-pressed</a> meggings stumptown plaid, pop-up taxidermy. Hoodie XOXO fingerstache scenester Echo Park. Plaid ugh Wes Anderson, freegan pug selvage fanny pack leggings pickled food truck DIY irony Banksy.</p>

<h4 id="hipster-list">Hipster list</h4>
<ul>
    <li>brunch</li>
    <li>fixie</li>
    <li>raybans</li>
    <li>messenger bag</li>
</ul>

<p>Hoodie Thundercats retro, tote bag 8-bit Godard craft beer gastropub. Truffaut Tumblr taxidermy, raw denim Kickstarter sartorial dreamcatcher. Quinoa chambray slow-carb salvia readymade, bicycle rights 90’s yr typewriter selfies letterpress cardigan vegan.</p>

<hr />

<p>Pug heirloom High Life vinyl swag, single-origin coffee four dollar toast taxidermy reprehenderit fap distillery master cleanse locavore. Est anim sapiente leggings Brooklyn ea. Thundercats locavore excepteur veniam eiusmod. Raw denim Truffaut Schlitz, migas sapiente Portland VHS twee Bushwick Marfa typewriter retro id keytar.</p>

<blockquote>
    We do not grow absolutely, chronologically. We grow sometimes in one dimension, and not in another, unevenly. We grow partially. We are relative. We are mature in one realm, childish in another.
    —Anais Nin
</blockquote>

<p>Fap aliqua qui, scenester pug Echo Park polaroid irony shabby chic ex cardigan church-key Odd Future accusamus. Blog stumptown sartorial squid, gastropub duis aesthetic Truffaut vero. Pinterest tilde twee, odio mumblecore jean shorts lumbersexual.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts" /><category term="formatting" /><category term="links" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[march & april, looking forward to summer]]></summary></entry></feed>